Chuang, Tieh-Hung

ironhead.chuang@gmail.com http://blog.ironhead.ninja/

Summary

Software developer with 10+ years of programming experience. Comfortable in large code bases and multithreading development. Write clear, maintainable code. Excellent debugging skills. Eager to explore new technologies.

Skills

- Programming: C/C++, Python, Java.
- Media player development, computer graphics, game development.

Experience

Staff Engineer, KKStream Limited

Taipei, Taiwan — August 2015 - Present

Accomplishments

- Developing an Android adaptive streaming player which has been installed on 100,000 ~ 500,000 devices.
- Knowledge sharing: Monte Carlo Algorithm.
- Knowledge sharing: Neural Network.

Technical Consultant, Next Media Animation

Taipei, Taiwan — July 2012 - July 2015

Provide solutions for iOS, rendering & video playback. Set up projects and improve junior developers' programming skills.

Involved projects

- News player iOS app.
- Facial expression avatar iOS app.
- Toon effect tool optimization (object labeling, silhouette rendering, CUDA)
- Augmented reality system optimization.
- Facial expression tool optimization.
- In-house video player design.

Game Developer, Self-Employed

Taipei, Taiwan — July 2011 - July 2015

Led the development of an iOS game app (P.R.O.B.E.).

Accomplishments

- Set up milestones and development pipelines.
- Developed a universal puzzle game app along with the game engine and editor.

R&D Engineer, Next Media Animation

Taipei, Taiwan — August 2009 - June 2011

Developed computer graphics & vision tools.

Accomplishments

- Optimised tool of the light stage to 5x faster using CUDA.
- Developed a direct show filter to reduce efforts of all camera-related projects.
- Developed a tool to speed up face model stitching.
- Knowledge sharing: Nvidia CUDA programming.
- Knowledge sharing: high dynamic range imaging.

Senior Software Engineer, Corel Corporation

Taipei, Taiwan — December 2006 - August 2009

Developed components and applications on windows. Handled rendering issues. Shared 3d rendering knowledge.

Accomplishments

- Developed a component to use webcam of laptops as light sensors.
- Developed a standalone TV application.
- Enhanced Direct 3D UI library.
- Handled rendering issues for TV team.

Software Engineer, InterVideo

Taipei, Taiwan — March 2006 - December 2006

Accomplishments

- Developed a TV ActiveX component to reduce efforts of TV application development.
- Secured shipment of multimedia application on embedded XP.

Software Engineer, DynaColor, Inc.

Taipei, Taiwan — January 2004 - February 2006

Developed Windows applications and tools.

Accomplishments

- Developed Windows applications of digital video recorders.
- Developed a Windows application to manage multiple digital video recorder systems.
- Developed an editor to simplify font editing for embedded systems.

Education

National Taiwan University

B.S. in Physics — 1997 - 2001